Michael Arreguin

Geospatial Information Systems Professional (916) 837 - 7835

PROFILE

GIS professional with experience administrating Enterprise GIS solutions, completing complex geospatial projects within budgeted timeframes, acting as a liaison between GIS and interdepartmental teams, and constantly staying abreast of new innovation within the GIS industry.

EXPERIENCE

GIS and Data Management Specialist, Recology, Sacramento/Remote, CA - 2019 - Present

Optimize truck routes for operational efficiency. Use Routesmart and Esri software to perform reroute analysis and automate nightly routing for early morning routes via Python and VBscript. Guide non-corporate GIS specialist on specialized projects. Specialized projects include mobile data collection, raster analysis, mapping requests, web mapping, and customized scripts for automation. Conduct GIS trainings within other departments. Administer the organization's ArcGIS Online account.

GIS Analyst/Programmer, Computer Task Group, Fairfield, CA - 2018 - 2019 Perform complex geospatial analysis for the DA, engineering department, and environmental resources department as a contractor for the County of Solano. Create scripts for automating mapping tasks. Create display maps using ArcMap, ArcPro, and Adobe Illustrator. Convert existing geospatial layers to the Local Government Information Model schema, and update parcel layer using the parcel fabric Esri model. Create web maps for internal and external use.

GIS Technician, County of Tuolumne, Sonora, CA – 2017 - 2018

Perform geospatial database updates for key layers used by several county divisions. Update and create feature datasets. Maintain and create public-facing and internal web maps using ArcGIS Online and Portal for ArcGIS. Write Python and VBA scripts to create ArcGIS for Desktop tools to automate tasks for other departments. Update cadastral parcel layers. Work closely with Tree Mortality and Fire to track dead trees as they relate to infrastructure and fire threat, and create visuals to present findings.

Jr. Data Analyst, VSOLVIT, Sonora, CA - 2016 - 2017

Develop technical training. Test software applications in development for enterprise GIS solutions. Work closely with the QA team and development team to find bugs in VSolvit applications. Develop scripts to automate testing.

Specialist, Apple, Santa Barbara, CA - 2011 - 2013

Sales of Apple products & third party retailers sold in the Apple store. Orchestrate training workshops on apple products & software. Ensure high customer satisfaction by tactfully approaching, questioning, positioning, listening, & presenting a complete solution for customers & small businesses.

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin at Madison, Madison, WI — Master of Science in GIS (programming emphasis), 2016-2020

University of California at Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA - Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology, 2012 - 2014

SKILLS

ArcMap (latest), ArcPro, ArcGIS Enterprise, QGIS, SQL, Python Scripting, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Arcpy, Cartographic Design, LiDAR analysis, Mapbox GL JS, Leaflet, Route Optimization, Routesmart, Terrain Mapping, Raster Analysis, Database Design, Adobe Creative Suite, GDAL, OGR, General Tech Support, Customer Service, QA Testing

LinkedIn GitHub